<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Pickering.Cloud Blog</title>
    <link>/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Pickering.Cloud Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Blog {0} - Jan 2025</title>
      <link>/posts/blog-0---jan-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/blog-0---jan-2025/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;early-days&#34;&gt;Early Days&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From an early age, gaming wasn&amp;rsquo;t just a pastime for me; it was the gateway to a lifelong fascination with technology. I remember the thrill of assembling my first gaming PC with support from friends in April 2020. This experience ignited my interest in coding, leading me to experiment with Python, even if my initial projects were more fun than functional.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;first-it-job&#34;&gt;First IT Job&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Leaving the familiar routine of McDonald&amp;rsquo;s in August 2021, after spending the first 5 years of my working life there, I plunged into the exciting yet daunting world of IT. My first role at New Look’s help desk felt like stepping into uncharted territory, but I was eager to prove myself. I was hired on a fixed-term contract, with principal responsibility of managing the iPad devices that were used in the retail stores daily which included provisioning the devices, amending the build being applied, managing the CMDB (Configuration Management Database), and organising the logistics of both shipping the devices to stores, and collecting faulty devices. For those unaware, a CMDB holds data relating to IT assets. Only a few months down the line, I was offered a permanent position which increased my responsibilities to also include supporting end users across offices and retail stores with basic IT support requests.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content>&lt;h2 id=&#34;early-days&#34;&gt;Early Days&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From an early age, gaming wasn&amp;rsquo;t just a pastime for me; it was the gateway to a lifelong fascination with technology. I remember the thrill of assembling my first gaming PC with support from friends in April 2020. This experience ignited my interest in coding, leading me to experiment with Python, even if my initial projects were more fun than functional.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;first-it-job&#34;&gt;First IT Job&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Leaving the familiar routine of McDonald&amp;rsquo;s in August 2021, after spending the first 5 years of my working life there, I plunged into the exciting yet daunting world of IT. My first role at New Look’s help desk felt like stepping into uncharted territory, but I was eager to prove myself. I was hired on a fixed-term contract, with principal responsibility of managing the iPad devices that were used in the retail stores daily which included provisioning the devices, amending the build being applied, managing the CMDB (Configuration Management Database), and organising the logistics of both shipping the devices to stores, and collecting faulty devices. For those unaware, a CMDB holds data relating to IT assets. Only a few months down the line, I was offered a permanent position which increased my responsibilities to also include supporting end users across offices and retail stores with basic IT support requests.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;continuation-of-it-career&#34;&gt;Continuation of IT Career&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In March the following year, I then moved up to the 2nd line End User Compute team, where I started taking more responsibility for supporting our end users with more complex queries, learning PowerShell, and diving deeper into the workings of a computer - as well as being encouraged to work towards some Microsoft Certifications by my line management. While working in the EUC team, I was able to earn 3 foundation certifications (Azure, M365, Security &amp;amp; Compliance) as well as the now retired M365 Security Administrator Associate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In July 2023, I was then given the massive opportunity to work with the 3rd line Technical Services team on a secondment to be a direct link between infrastructure support and security operations. This involved moving away from previous AV solution and onboarding the new solution, managing the patching of the server estate, and utilising Azure Resource Manager, through Azure Arc, to start automated patching of less critical servers. This secondment gave me vital server management and troubleshooting skills, which then made me a prime candidate for the full time position which I gained in December 2023.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;future-goals&#34;&gt;Future Goals&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since then, I have developed my skills across areas of computing including web design, PowerShell, FTP, PKI and certificates, and identity and access management. I intend to continue my journey moving forward by investigating infrastructure as code, notably Terraform, and penetration testing skills. The idea behind this blog is to track my efforts, as well as to give me a platform to reflect on new technologies and things I have learned.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let me know your IT journey so far or how you started in IT in the comments below!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
